HELSINKI, FINLAND +358 449440279

SENIOR UX/UI DESIGNER - SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

ALPACA.THIAGO@GMAIL.COM

SKYPE: ALPACA.THIAGO

HTTPS://FI.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/THIAGOTOMASI

THIAGOTOMASI.COM

Thiago Tarouco Tomasi

SKILLS AND ABILITIES

Hi my name is Thiago Tomasi, I have 29 year old, I have a degree in advertising and marketing at ESPM and I am completing my post graduate in Strategic Design at Unisinos. I had an international experience in Dublin in Ireland for 1 year.

In my 8 years of experience the UX/UI Designer and Front End Developer I had the opportunity to work on projects of national and international big companies, always pursuing excellencein my work.

I have experience in agile environments where the result of the work can be measured continuously in the construction process of the projects. I believe in the Lean methodology and Design Sprint and always seeking agility to create prototypes.

As front-end developer (HTML / CSS - SASS, Stylus / Javascript) and my graduation in communication and marketing I relate well between the development and business teams, looking to advocate about the the end user needs without losing focus on the result in the business the client is looking for.

In addition, I'm a mentor of Careers Office from PUCRS in Design field, helping to develop young talents in their careers.

Specialties

UX & UI Design

- Personas
- Quantitative/Qualitative research
- Customer journey mapping
- Usability Testing
- A/B Testing
- Idea Valuation

Front-End Development

- Responsive development
- CSS Architecture CSS3/Stylus/Sass
- JavaScript Architecture Javascript
- GruntJs/Gulp
- Bower
- GIT

EXPERIENCE

SPORTACAM - UX/UI DESIGNER LEAD

[Apr. 2016 - Now]

At this company I was responsible for product development, participating in the strategic planning trough the technical development of products, together with the marketing and engineering team.

INEVENT – UX/UI DESIGNER & FRONT END DEVELOPER LEAD

[Aug. 2015 - Apr. 2016]

I'm responsible of acting as an user advocate, and showing his importance in process of building web systems, from beginning to the validation of the solutions, leading the Front End and UX Design Team.

FREELANCER - SENIOR UI & UX DESIGNER | SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

[2007 - Abr.2016]

As a freelancer had the opportunity to work on projects of national and international big and small companies, as a front-end developer and UI & UX Designer.

AZION TECHNOLOGIES - UX/UI DESIGNER & FRONT END DEVELOPER LEAD

[Jan. 2014 - Aug. 2015]

I'm responsible of acting as an user advocate, and showing his importance in process of building web systems, from beginning to the validation of the solutions, leading the Front End and UX Design Team.

INTERACTION DESIGN FOUNDATION – UX/UI DESIGNER & FRONT END DEVELOPER LEAD

[Mar. 2014 - Jun. 2015]

At this company I was responsible for learning platform development, participating in the strategic planning trough the technical development of the products.

EDUCATION

UNISINOS - PORTO ALEGRE - MASTER OF STRATEGIC DESIGN, INNOVATION AND SYSTEM-PRODUCT DESIGN

Master in partnership with POLI.design, Consorzio del Politecnico di Milano's Strategic Design course

ESPM - PORTO ALEGRE - ADVERTISING AND MARKETING

For completion of the course, I developed a study on the usability and information architecture for responsive web sites.

PUCRS - PORTO ALEGRE - INFORMATION SYSTEM

Course locked in 5th Semester

QUALIFICATION

HUMAN-CENTERED DESIGN FOR SOCIAL INNOVATION - +ACUMEN/IDEO - 2014

Human-Centered Design for Social Innovation is a seven-week course that will introduce you to the concepts of human-centered design and help you use the design process to create innovative, effective, and sustainable solutions for social change.

HUMAN COMPUTER INTERACTION - STANFORD/COURSERA - 2013

Helping build human-centered design skills, so that you have the principles and methods to create excellent interfaces with any technology.

UX DESIGN COURSE - 2013

One course to see what's behind of the UX Design.

Be more creative - National Autonomous University of Mexico / Coursera - 2013 All we can enhance our creativity through procedures, routines and simple protocols. This course developed these skills and abilities through challenges that activate our talents to find original solutions.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING FOR STARTUPS AND DIGITAL ENTREPRENEURSHIP / STHART-FGV – 2013

Sthart, 100 people selected from among 2,500 and offered a three-week immersion learning about business and digital market.